遠古最偉大的文明
The greatest civilizations of antiquity...
是對電能的使用
running on electrical power.
電力是那些古文明中運用嫻熟
Electricity is one of those things that ancient cultures seem
■
而我們至今仍然無法玩轉的東西之一
to be harnessing in ways that we still can't wrap our brain around.
吉薩的大金字塔
Energy generating microwaves,
可以產生發電微波
produced at the Great Pyramid of Giza.
他們使用能量不足為奇
The question is not they  used power,
問題是他們是從哪得到
the question is where did they get the knowledge
關於製造能量的知識的？
with which they created the power?
地球包裹著一層無線能量網
And a wireless energy grid that crossed the globe.
它是一個為這些神明供給宇宙能量的發射器
It was a transmitter of this cosmic power that fed these celestial beings.
是否我們的遠古先人
Could our ancient ancestors
精通駕馭能量和製造能量的技術？
have mastered the ability to harness and create power?
如果是這樣
If so,
這些先進的知識起源何處？
where might this advanced knowledge have come from?
或許我們可以從外星人所使用的
This evidence of some nuclear reaction,
遠古發電廠的遺跡中找到一些
what we may be seeing is the residue
關於使用核反應的證據
of one of the ancient power plants used by extraterrestrials.
世界上有數百萬人相信
Millions of people around the world believe
外星生物曾造訪過我們
we have been visited in the past by extraterrestrial beings.
如果這是真的呢?
What if it were true?
遠古外星人真的幫我們塑造了歷史嗎?
Did ancient aliens really help to shape our history?
在這些遠古發電廠的背後隱藏著
And what secrets of ancient energy sources
怎樣的關於遠古能源的秘密？
may be unlocked at these alien power plants?
它們是誰？
它們為何而來？
它們留下了什麼？
它們去了何處？
它們會再次歸來嗎？
遠  古  外  星  人
外  星  人  的  發  電  廠
以色列 耶路撒冷 西石
The Western Stone, Jerusalem, Israel.
120萬磅
1.2 million pounds.
埃及 底比斯 拉美西斯雕像
The Ramesseum statue, Thebes, Egypt.
200萬磅
Two million pounds.
黎巴嫩 巴勒貝克 朱庇特神廟的巨石牌坊
The Trilithon at the Temple of Jupiter, Baalbek, Lebanon.
480萬磅
4.8 million pounds.
主流考古學家認為世界各地那些
All over the world, ancient sites reveal engineering feats
揭露工程壯舉的古代遺跡是由奴隸和
that mainstream archeology believe were achieved
簡單的工具造就的
with slave labor and simple tools.
我深信這些
The reason why I am convinced
古老的石塊是先進工藝的產物
that sophisticated technology was implemented in these ancient rocks
因為如果我們來到採石場
is because if we go to a stone quarry today
光是從機械的角度來看
and look at the scope of machinery required
即便現在想要完成相同的事情
to accomplish similar things,
我們需要的機器將是相當巨大的
well, those machines are huge.
那就是動力機械
They're power machines.
強大的工具
Powerful tools.
如果主流考古學家將這些解釋為
And if the mainstream archeology explanation is given that
東西是由黑曜石或者雞骨石
all of this stuff was accomplished with obsidian
...所建成的
or with chicken bones...
很抱歉 這不成立
I'm sorry, it doesn't hold up.
有些廟宇建造用料
There are temples  that are built using blocks
在50噸到200噸之間
that range from 50 to 200 tons.
這些需要搬運的建築材料
They're just far too big
對於沒有輪子沒有滑輪
for people who didn't have the wheel,
沒有任何設備的人來說
who didn't have the pulley,who didn't have any
實在是太巨大了
facilities to move these blocks.
對我來說 這是一個需要解釋的謎團
So to me, there is a mystery there that needs to be explained.
或者那是一種我們不瞭解的技術
Either a technology that we don't understand,
亦或是可以更大膽些推測這是某種外界影響
or, if one wants to go very speculative, an external influence.
是否那時候人們的力量
Could the strength  of men alone
就已經足夠搞定如此巨大的成就？
have been enough to manage such colossal efforts?
又或者這些工程奇跡還需要更多支持？
Or did these marvels of engineering require something more?
加利福尼亞 河濱市 石頭谷材料採石場
Stone Valley Materials Quarry; Riverside, California.
2012年2月
February, 2012.
一塊重達68萬磅的花崗岩將作為
A massive 680,000-pound granite monolith is prepped
一件洛杉磯藝術博物館展會的展品
to travel over 100 miles to become part of an exhibit
被搬運100英里
at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art.
要移動這塊巨石需要
Workers from 100 utility crews,
100個公用單位的工作人員
a 1.4 million pound crane,
140多萬磅的起重機
and a 44-axel tractor-trailer rig
和一台馬力超過2400的44節牽引掛車
with over 2400 horsepower are needed to move the rock.
首先需要用液壓將巨石從地面托起
It's going to  require hydraulically jacking the boulder up off the ground,
這個過程令人難以置信的困難...
which is incredibly difficult in itself...
然後在它下方架設
building steel girders underneath it,
帶有208個輪胎的鋼樑
placing 208 tires underneath those steel girders,
然後用上一個拉力和一個推力
having one power unit pulling it and one pushing it,
在這樣的條件下
and still, after all of that,
仍然只能做到1小時移動5英里
only achieving about five miles an hour.
這塊叫「懸浮的石塊」的巨石
The boulder, called "Levitated Mass"
以現代建築標準來說是一個巨大的負載...
is a gigantic payload by modern construction standards...
但是與古代建築者所搬運的建築塊相比
but it is small when compared to many of the solid blocks
它顯得很小
moved by ancient builders.
對我而言
From my perspective,
要移動一塊340噸重的巨石在缺少現代...
it is almost impossible to take the 340 ton rock
現今技術的條件下幾乎是不可能的
and move it without modern...day technology.
這令我困惑
It baffles my mind.
我實在..實在...實在是無法想像
I have-I have... I have no idea.
考慮這件事是在是太瘋狂了
It's crazy to think about.
我們的祖先是如何在
How did our ancestors move monoliths,
缺乏高性能機械的條件下
some over five times the size of Levitated Mass
移動比「懸浮的石塊」重五倍的巨石？
without the aide of high-powered machines?
調查人員認為古人在移動巨石的時候
Researchers believe the ancients
用的不僅是力量
not only used power to move solid stone,
而且還對石塊進行了切割
but to cut it as well.
證據可以在安第斯山脈偏遠的
And the evidence can be found on a remote cliff face
懸壁下找到
buried in the Andes Mountains.
秘魯 奧林太坦坡鎮
Ollantaytambo, Peru.
這個古老山寨的城牆
The walls of this ancient mountain stronghold tell the story
令一些專家相信 曾經有數千工匠
of what some experts believe to have been thousands of craftsmen,
具備精湛的加工和切割石塊的技術
shaping and cutting solid stone with a precision
而如今我們要做到這些只能通過
that today could only be matched
高性能的機器
with high-powered machine tools.
我們發現了一些巨大的立方形石塊...
We find huge cube-like sections of stone...
安山巖 我們在它的表面找不到任何刮痕
andesite, which is very hard... have been removed from the mountain
有著這樣光滑表面的石塊
with such accuracy that
是很難從山上搬運走的
that we can't find a scratch in the surface.
同樣 它們的稜角也不鋒利...
The corners, also, are not sharp...
這些角相當的圓潤
they're perfectly rounded
沒人知道這是怎麼辦到的
and no one can explain how this could have been achieved.
能夠將幾噸重的石頭完美的砌到一起
The ability to fit perfectly fitting stones of several tons in weight together
中間的縫隙甚至連一根頭髮都塞不進
so that a single human hair can't fit in between them
這並不是付出汗水和時間就可以做到的
is not a question of sweat or man hours.
這是技術問題
It's a question of technology.
它確實被製造的十全十美
It's really done to perfection.
而且這並不只是將小石塊砌的完美無缺
And not just perfection with small blocks of stone,
而是重達數噸的石塊
but with blocks of stone weighing many, many tons.
我認為奧林太坦坡是世界範圍
I believe that Ollantaytambo is evidence of really advanced
人類先進文明和使用電力工具的證據
human civilization on Earth that was world-wide and had power tools.
但是 如果我們的祖先真的使用了
But if our ancestors really used
某種能量運行複雜的工具
sophisticated tools that ran on some sort of power,
那麼是否存在其他關於這種技術
might there have been other applications of this technology,
超越移動和切割石塊的運用？
beyond moving and cutting stone?
世界各地都存在那些蘊含著
All over the world  we have extraordinarily
非常先進的文明的城鎮系統
advanced civilizations with urban systems.
現在我們所使用的輸水系統、排污系統
The things we have today in delivery systems for water, for handling waste,
泵、非常複雜的灌溉和農業系統
pumps, very sophisticated farming and agriculture techniques
沒有任何一樣是從
that they should not have had
他們那傳承下來的他們所使用的技術
given the level of technology they worked with.
我們所得到的就只有那些
The only thing that we have leftover
古老建築所使用的建築古石
is the original stone that all these ancient structures were built in.
所有的一切都建立在石頭之上
Everything else that was built on top of it,
即使曾經可能有電子元件
that had to do potentially with electrical components,
它們也早就消失了
that has disappeared
因為只有石頭經受的起時間的考驗
because only stone withstands the test of time.
最主要的古代文明能夠達到這樣的程度
Is it possible that the most dominant civilizations of antiquity
是否是因為能源驅動技術？
were able to achieve such status because of energy-driven technologies?
如果是這樣 那麼這種能量源自何處？
And if so, what was the source of that power?
線索或許就在美索不達米亞的古文物中
Perhaps clues may be found among ancient Mesopotamian artifacts.
伊拉克國家博物館
The National Museum of Iraq.
1938年 博物館館長
In 1938, the museum director
在檔案中發現赤土陶罐和銅柱
discovers terra cotta pots and copper cylinders in the archives
或許曾被當成原電池使用
that may have been used as galvanic cells.
這個將近2000年歷史的設備
The nearly 2,000-year-old devices
被稱為「巴格達電池」
called "Baghdad Batteries"
人們認為它出現的時間比最早的電池
are believed to predate the invention of the cell battery
發明時間要早1000年
by more than 1,000 years.
考古學家推測
Archaeologists speculate
它們可能曾經用於給銀飾珠寶鍍金
they may have been used to electroplate gold onto silver for decorative jewelry.
目前我們在伊拉克發現了
The Baghdad Battery  that we've currently found in Iraq,
大概一打的巴格達電池
about a dozen of them,
它可以產生4V左右的電壓
it can generate around four volts.
如今 一支現代手電筒只需要9V的電池
Now, a current modern-day flashlight could be run by a nine-volt battery.
如果我們考慮到巴格達電池在這個尺寸可以產生4V電
So if we think of a Baghdad Battery around this size generating four volts,
那麼如果將它擴大到6英尺左右呢？
what if we increased the size to around six feet?
它可能能產生20V、30V、50V的電
That might generate 20, 30, 50 volts
並產生足夠的能量就和我們如今利用電能的方式一樣
and have the sufficient power to actually utilize energy in a way that we do today.
主流科學家人也認為巴格達電池
Mainstream scientists agree that the Baghdad Battery is evidence
是古人類有意識的製造能量
ancient man had the means to create power
運用能量的證據並且
and the understanding of how to apply it.
但是否存在使用電力的
But is there proof of even more complex devices
更複雜的證據？
that may have run on electricity?
吉薩高原以南370英里處矗立著哈索爾神廟
370 miles south of the Giza Plateau stands the Hathor Temple.
這座神廟有著近4000年的歷史
Approximately 4,000 years old,
神廟的通道上雕刻著奇怪的圖案
the halls of this monument are lined with curious images,
但是遠古外星人理論認為其中一個浮雕是
but one relief depicts what many ancient astronaut theorists believe
古人使用能量的證據
to be proof that the ancients used power.
他們稱之為「丹達臘燈泡」
They call it "The Dendera Bulb."
這是一個埃及丹達臘浮雕上的
Here is a replica of the bulb that's shown
燈泡的仿製品
in the Dendera reliefs in Egypt.
關於這個燈泡有趣的是
What's interesting about this bulb
事實上在牆雕上
is the fact that on the wall relief,
我們可以看到燈泡的插頭被
we see the bulb is actually plugged into
插入一個類似電源的地方
what appears to be a power source.
關於古埃及人擁有某種類似電燈的東西
The whole idea that the ancient Egyptians had
而且這東西可能遍佈
some kind of electrical lighting,
世界各地神廟的想法...
and this was something that happened in probably temples around the world...
埃及考古學家們一直對於人們是如何
It baffles Egyptologists how people deep underground
在沒有火和光的地下刻畫這些天花板感到困惑
would be able to paint these ceilings without fires and lights.
他們的解釋是埃及人在白天時
Their explanation right now
使用某種複雜的反射系統
is that they used a complex system of mirrors to move light,
在幾分鐘內將光線
at just a few minutes during the day,
引入這些古墓
down deep inside these tombs.
但是另一個解釋就是
But another explanation, of course,
或許他們其實擁有電燈
would be they actually had electrical lights.
是否我們的祖先早在我們現代人之前
Did our ancestors have an understanding
數千年就懂得如何製造能量？
of how to generate power thousands of years before modern man?
或者如遠古外星人理論所認為的
Or is it possible that they received the knowledge from some otherworldly source,
他們是從外星得到這些知識的？
as some ancient astronaut theorists contend?
電力是那些古文明中運用嫻熟
Electricity is one of those things that ancient cultures seem to be harnessing
而我們如今仍然無法玩轉的東西之一
in ways that we still can't wrap our brain around.
所以在我們看到電這樣的東西時
So it's very possible that when we look at things like electricity,
不禁會考慮他們是從哪得到的信息？
where would they get this information?
我們有各種各樣的故事、神話和傳說
We have all sorts of stories, mythologies and legends
將之解釋為是上帝所為
that could be interpreted as gods who,
事實上 這是對外星人以能量的形式
in reality, were misinterpreted extraterrestrials
贈與人類技術的事實的誤解
gifting man with technology in the form of power.
例如 舊約中的上帝說"要有光"
For example, when God said, "Let there be light" in the Old Testament,
或者普羅米修斯贈予人類火種
or when Prometheus gave fire to man.
阿波羅神廟燃燒的灌木和永恆的火焰
The Burning Bush and the Eternal Flame at the Temple of Apollo,
可以想見 都是因為技術
all of that conceivably could have been technology.
問題不是他們是否使用了電能
The question is not if they used power,
問題是他們從哪得到了製造電能的方法？
the question is where did they get the knowledge with which they created the power?
是否在古文明的遺跡中真的能找到
Is there really evidence among the ruins of ancient civilizations
人們通過複雜的技術使用電能的證據？
that man had access to sophisticated technologies that ran on power?
如果是這樣
If so,
那個產生這些能量的神秘發電廠在哪？
where are the mysterious power plants that generated the energy?
也許它們仍在原地
Perhaps they're still here,
就隱藏在我們的視線之中
hiding in plain sight.
埃及 吉薩金字塔群
The Giza Necropolis,Egypt.
1993年
1993.
一隊工程師使用遙控相機
A team of engineers uses a remotely operated camera
試圖發現大金字塔中通往皇后室的
in an attempt to discover the true function of what is believed to be an airshaft
那條被認為是通風井的通道的真正的功能
leading from the supposed Queen's Chamber of the Great Pyramid
1872年第一次發現時
First discovered in 1872,
考古學家經過長時間的思考
archaeologists long considered
認為這些狹窄的通道是用來通風的
these narrow tunnels to be ventilation ducts.
這個機器人通過了那個對人類或者
This robot traveled up this small shaft which was
任何形式的裝置來說都太狹小的通道
too small for a human or any type of device to go through
然後它突然發現了一扇
and all of the sudden it finds a closed door
裝著兩個金屬鉸鏈的關閉的門
hinged by two little metal clamps.
主流考古學學家認為
According to mainstream archaeologists,
那個門和把手是有意裝上的
the door and metal handles were intentionally built
這條通道象徵著皇后通往來世的
as a symbolic passageway that the queen would travel through
道路
to the afterlife.
但是有些研究者對此懷有疑問
But some researchers have questioned why this passageway
為什麼這條通道會被有意設計成閉塞的
would have been designed with a deliberate blockage.
而又為什麼...
And why...
而又為什麼...在一個佈滿了巨大金字塔的高原上
on a plateau filled with monumental pyramids
被認為是皇陵的...
believed to serve as royal tombs...
是唯一一座有著一扇這樣的門的大金字塔？
is the Great Pyramid the only one with such a door?
埃及考古學家們更願意相信
Egyptologists are very  much fond of saying
這些金字塔是墳墓
that pyramids are tombs and
並且在過去曾被盜墓者洗劫過
that they have been robbed at some point in the past.
但事實上在20世紀時我們發現了一批金字塔
But the fact is that we have found in the 20th century a number of pyramids
其中心的國王室
whose central king's chamber,
可以說是完整的
so to speak, is intact.
而當人們打開石棺後發現
And when they opened the sarcophagus they found
石棺內是空的
that sarcophagus to be empty as well.
如果大金字塔不是墳墓
If the Great Pyramid was not a tomb,
那麼它的真是用途會是什麼？
what may have been its true purpose?
2011年5月 另一隊研究人員著手對
In May 2011, another team of researchers set out to further
皇后室的閉塞通風口做進一步的調查
explore the blocked airshaft in the Queen's Chamber.
這一次 研究人員用一個裝備有蛇形相機的
This time, the crew used a robot equipped with a micro-snake camera
機器人鑽過了一個洞並且探照出了門另一測的景象
to slip through a hole and reveal what was beyond the door.
當他們確實穿過這個小門後
When they actually penetrated this small door
他們發現了金字塔中隱藏著一個房間
they found a hidden room within the pyramid.
他們所發現的是一些銅件或者金屬物件
What they found was copper fittings or the metal fittings.
門背後的這些金屬物件的另一個特點就是
Another feature of the back of these metal fittings
它一側的環看起來像是被侵蝕了
was that on one side the loop looked like it was corroded.
那個照相機向下拍攝地面
The camera also looked down and scanned the floor and
然後我們看到了紅色的標記
what we saw was red markings.
我對這些符號的理解是它們是電工符號
My interpretation of those were they were electrical symbols.
但它們為什麼會在那裡？
But why were they there?
是否這些工件就是證明
Could these artifacts be actual evidence
這個建築中曾經通電的證據？
that electricity once coursed through the structure?
如果這樣 那麼是否如一些研究人員所
And if so, could the Great Pyramid of Giza
主張的那樣 吉薩大金字塔的功用並不是皇陵
have been built to serve as... not a royal tomb...
而是發電廠？
but a power plant, as some researchers contend?
如果我們拋開墳墓理論 只看金字塔本身
If we dismiss the tomb theory and we look at the pyramid itself,
我們會看到一些現代工程師可以理解
we see something that modern engineers can really
和明白的事情
tune into and understand.
我們所看到的是一座非常非常精確的建築
What we have is a very, very precise building that has the
它的精度達到了零點幾英吋
precision of a fraction of an inch.
這是非常值得注意的
It's something that is very noteworthy
而不只是一個簡單農耕文化的象徵
and not indicative of a simple agrarian culture.
所以我們所看到的幾乎是一台機器
So what we have is something that is almost like a machine.
如果大金字塔真的是一台複雜的機器
If the Great Pyramid was a sophisticated machine,
而且可能製造能量
potentially capable of creating energy,
那麼它是如何運轉的？
how could it have worked?
一些研究人員認為研究金字塔的地下結構
Some researchers believe clues can be found
可以找到線索
by exploring underneath the structure.
2000年 海事工程師約翰·卡德曼
In 2000, maritime engineer John Cadman
提出了一個理論
proposed a theory that
埃及人從附近的尼羅河用泵
the Egyptians pumped water from the nearby Nile River
抽水到大金字塔底下的小室中
into a small chamber underneath the Great Pyramid.
這個泵可以創造出強烈到可以引起
The pump could then create intense hydraulic pressure
金字塔震動的液壓壓力
that would cause the entire pyramid to vibrate.
在那個地下室中存在一些表明
In the subterranean chamber there is some evidence that shows
那裡有過水的證據
that there had been water present in it,
那裡的地面上有被水侵蝕的痕跡
and that there's water erosion on the floor,
稍高的地方侵蝕就弱些
and then up in the thin area.
同時也因為它是一個液壓脈衝發生器
And then also, because it was a hydraulic pulse generator.
所以那裡會有一個稀疏波
So you have a rarefaction wave,
那是一個非常低的壓力波
which is an extremely low pressure wave,
它會撞擊到天花板上
which would have struck the ceiling
讓天花板受損
and the ceiling is actually chipped.
這樣會有一個實際的壓力波
And that would have been from the actual
衝擊天花板
compression waves hitting the ceiling.
這很顯然
It's very evident.
如果卡德曼的理論被證實是對的
If Cadman's theory proves true,
那麼液壓脈衝的作用是什麼？
what would have been the purpose of the hydraulic pulse?
工程師克裡斯·鄧恩認為答案可以在
Engineer Chris Dunn believes the answer can be found
被稱為皇后室的通風井中找到
by further examination of the shafts in what some call the Queen's Chamber,
在那裡找到了鋅和鹽酸的痕跡
where traces of zinc and hydrochloric acid have been discovered.
我認為從北面的通道進入的是水化鋅溶液
I believe the chemical coming in through the northern shaft was hydrated zinc
而從南面的通道
and the other chemical coming through the southern shaft
進入的則是稀鹽酸
and into the chamber was dilute hydrochloric acid.
這就是內室牆壁的樣子
These are actually seen on the chamber walls.
鄧恩認為這兩種化學藥品被從通道中倒下
Dunn suggests that the two chemicals were poured down through the shafts
然後在皇后室中混合到一起觸發氧化反應
and then mixed together inside the Queen's Chamber, triggering combustion.
這個器皿代表皇后室
This vessel represents the Queen's Chamber.
我們將從這個管口導入水化鋅溶液...
Into the tubes we're going to pour hydrated zinc...
然後鹽酸
and then hydrochloric acid.
當你將這兩種溶液混合
When you bring these two liquids together,
就會發生化學反應
a chemical reaction occurs,
而這個反應的產物之一就是氫氣
and a product of that chemical reaction is hydrogen.
你可以看到水霧 氫氣從管口溢出
And you can see the vapor, the hydrogen, escaping through the chimney.
然後就有了這個反應
And there you have the reaction.
鄧恩產生的氫氣
Dunn speculates that the hydrogen gas
是通過皇后室進入國王室
traveled from the Queen's Chamber into the King's Chamber.
然後地下池的震動將氫原子
Then the vibrations from the subterranean pool
激發成微波能量束
energized the hydrogen atoms into a microwave energy beam.
證明使用氫氣的證據
The evidence that indicates the use of hydrogen
可以在國王室中找到
can be found in the King's chamber.
國王室中有一個大小為8.4×4.8的通道
There is a shaft in the King's Chamber,
剛好適用於一個微波激射器的波導管
has dimensions of 8.4 by 4.8, which would be suitable for a wave guide for a MASER,
或者一個受激發射微波放大微波
or a microwave amplification through stimulated emission radiation.
就此 我們可以對氫氣的用途提出
And from there, we can actually propose many different ideas
無數種猜測
of what they did with it.
是否在遙遠的過去吉薩大金字塔
Might the great Pyramid of Giza
確實是用來製造能量的？
actually have created power in the remote past?
是否是這種能量讓早期建築者先進的工具
And is it possible that energy
和類似丹達臘燈泡這樣的裝置
ran the advanced tools of early builders
運轉起來的？
and devices like the Dendera Bulb?
我們可以充分發揮我們的想像力
We can use our imaginations and, uh,
將各種可以使用這種能量的設備與之聯繫
come up with all kinds of devices to power with that kind of energy.
從簡單的家用電器直到高度先進的航天器
Uh, from simple domestic appliances to highly advanced spacecraft.
我是指所有的東西都有可能
I mean all things are possible.
古埃及人在古王國時期
The ancient Egyptians demonstrated
創造的所有物件上都展示出了
an exceptional level of skill
一個特殊的技能水平
in everything that they created during the Old Kingdom,
但仍然存在疑問...
but the question remains...
這些是他們自己做到的
did they do it on their own,
還是說他們從地球外得到了
or did they have some access
相關的信息或技術？
to information or technology that's not of this Earth?
如果說吉薩 事實上 是一個發電廠
If Giza was, in fact, a power plant,
那麼是否如遠古外星人理論所認為的那樣
could the energy have been used for some otherworldly purpose,
它所產生的能量是用於一些與外星相關的目的？
as some ancient astronaut theorists suggest?
如果吉薩產生的能量如此巨大
And if the power coming from Giza was that strong,
那麼它是否傳遍了埃及？
could it have traveled beyond Egypt?
答案或許可以在一種材料中找到
Answers may be found in a material that connects Giza
它將吉薩和一種遍及世界各地的特殊
to a special kind of monolith, one that exists on continents
巨石聯繫在一起
all over the world.
埃及 孟斐斯 阿布高拉博太陽神廟
The sun temple at Abu Gorab Memphis, Egypt.
1898年 柏林博物館的一個挖掘隊
In 1898, an excavation team with the Berlin Museum
發現了一座巨型方尖碑的地基
discovered the base of a massive obelisk estimated
預計這座碑高超過160英尺
to have once stood at over 160 feet tall.
根據埃德福的古埃及建築手冊
According to the ancient Egyptian building texts from Edfu,
阿布高拉博神廟被稱為「眾神之所」
Abu Gorab was known as the "Place of the Gods."
埃及考古學家們認為這是古人所信奉的
Egyptologists know it as a place where the ancients
具有神聖能量的風水寶地
connected with divine energies.
據說這是法老王和祭司通過
It is said that this is the very place where pharaohs
使用方尖碑的共振傳播
and priests experienced heightened awareness
熟練提高精神力的特殊場所
through the use of vibrations transmitted through the obelisk.
這個古老的方尖碑曾被當做測量地標
This ancient obelisk was used as a geodetic marker,
用於定位某些類型的古能源
pinpointing the source of some type of ancient energy.
或許不是精神力
Maybe not spiritual energy,
而是某種他們能夠駕馭的物理能量
but actual physical energy that they were able to harness.
雖然在世界各地發現了
While scholars believe Abu Gorab
數百種類似的方尖碑
was home to one of the largest obelisks ever constructed,
然而學者們認為阿布高拉博神廟是
similar-shaped monoliths have been found in
有史以來最巨大的一座
hundreds of variations all over the world.
不適合隱蔽、儲物 或是更高的制高點
Unsuitable for shelter, storage, or a higher vantage point,
方尖碑被賦予了更強大的用途
could obelisks have served another more powerful purpose.
有證據表明方尖碑在挖掘
There's evidence that obelisks are tapping in
地球的部分自然能源
to this natural energy that's part of the Earth.
這個理論就是取得地球的這些自然資源
The whole concept is to take these natural energies
並且使用這些資源
of the Earth and manipulate them.
這種能量很微弱
It's a subtle energy,
但是對於那些具有可以發現
but for those who have the devices
並探測這種能量的設備和技術的人來說
and technology to see and measure this energy,
這是可以使用的能量
it's something that can be used.
我認為方尖碑像是一種針對地球的針灸針
I believe obelisks are kind of like acupuncture needles for the Earth,
可以集中能量甚至解決地球
focusing and possibly healing Earth energy
能量分佈不均的問題
meridians that are not balanced,
而古文化知道如何做到這樣
and that the ancient cultures knew how to do that.
大量的方尖碑都是構建都是使用花崗岩
A vast number of obelisks are constructed from granite...
這是一種富含能量響應
a stone containing high concentrations
石英晶體的石頭
of energy-responsive quartz crystal.
由於其晶體結構
Because of its crystalline structure,
石英具有將地球自然電振動轉化為
quartz has the ability to convert the Earth's natural electrical vibrations
可用能量的性質
into usable energy by a property known
即壓電效應
as piezo-electricity.
壓電是由於振動或者振蕩
The piezo is for the vibrating or oscillating,
而電流是源於電能
and the electric is for electric.
這就意味著你可以使用電能讓它們進行
What this means is that you can use electricity
機械振蕩
to make them vibrate mechanically.
而當它們進行機械振蕩時就會發電
And when they vibrate mechanically they can generate electricity.
晶體被用於整個歷史中的
Crystals have been used throughout all of history
各種發明、各種技術
for various inventions, various technologies,
並且實現各種功效
and for getting things done.
你戴在手腕上的手錶可能就是一種
Your watch that you wear on your wrist could be
使用晶體的技術
a technology that uses crystals.
晶體實際上是一種用於轉變
Crystals are literally a tool and a technology that's
能量的工具和技術
essentially for transducing energy,
它可以將能量從一種狀態
and that is taking energy in one state
完全轉化成另一種狀態
and essentially converting it to another state.
是否豎立方尖碑的古文化
Is it possible the ancient cultures that erected obelisks
對於石英的高科技性能有所瞭解？
had some understanding of the high-tech properties of quartz?
如若如此 他們是否曾用方尖碑
And if so, could they have used obelisks
進行遠距離的能量傳輸？
to transmit energy over vast distances?
遠古外星人理論認為答案是肯定的
Ancient astronaut theorists believe the answer is yes,
而證據可以通過研究
and that evidence can be found
尼古拉·特斯拉的工作得到
by studying the work of Nicola Tesla.
1899年七月 著名科學家（特斯拉）
In July 1899, the famed scientist
聲稱發明了一種可以在無線的情況下通過空氣
claimed to have invented a way to transmit electricity through the air,
向全世界輸電的方法
wirelessly, all over the world.
通過利用地球的自然導電性...
By harnessing the Earth's natural conductivity...
或者特斯拉稱為「駐波」的東西...
or what Tesla called "standing waves"...
巨型發射器可以無限量發送和接收電力
giant transmitters could send and receive limitless amounts of electricity,
就像無形的水流
flowing like invisible water.
他的系統中一個關鍵的成分就是石英晶體
And one of the key components in his system was quartz crystal.
我們通常用所謂的傳播形式
Typically when we deal with the energy of electromagnetic
來處理電磁波的能量
waves it's in what we call a propagating form.
它就像是手電筒...
It's like the flashlight...
你打開它 它就發生位移
you turn it on and it moves.
它可以通過空間從一個地方傳播到另一個地方
It propagates through space and goes from one place to another.
駐波是一種與之不同的現象
A standing wave is kind of a different phenomena
因為波僅在一個地方上下震盪
because the wave just oscillates in one place up and down,
而能量是在兩個不同區域之間來回運動
and the energy goes in between two different regions, back and forth.
特斯拉提出並且試圖建立起這個
Tesla was proposing  and tried to build
無線能量系統
this system of wireless power.
他在紐約長島建立了沃登克裡弗塔
He built the Wardenclyffe Tower on Long Island in New York.
特斯拉試著將這個塔吊到一個發電廠上方
Tesla was going to then hook this tower up to a power plant
然後他要嘗試發送電力
and he was going to broadcast electricity.
據他所說 反重力飛艇將會從這些塔
According to him, antigravity airships would draw power
獲得能量
from these towers.
船舶、汽車和其他發電廠也可以由無線能量
Ships, cars and other power plants could also draw
傳輸處獲得能量
from this broadcast power.
特斯拉的技術突破是一種
Was Tesla's technological breakthrough
現代科技創新
a modern scientific innovation,
或者它只是重現了古代遺失的技術？
or could it have been a rediscovery of a lost alien technology?
一些研究人員認為 就如特斯拉一樣
Some researchers believe that, like Tesla,
古代建築者發現了駕馭和傳播
ancient builders discovered the ability to harness
地球能量的方法
and broadcast Earth's power,
而金字塔就是古代的
and the ancient equivalent to Tesla's Wardenclyffe Tower
特斯拉沃登克裡弗塔
may have been the Great Pyramid.
這個巨大的歷史遺跡牆體中含有
The walls of this massive monument
高濃度的石英晶體
contain a high concentration of quartz crystal,
有人認為金字塔
and some believe the Great Pyramid,
連同方尖碑一起
in conjunction with the obelisks,
組成了全球無線能源工作網
made up what may have been a global wireless energy network.
金字塔實際上是大地機械裝置
The pyramids were actually geo-mechanical devices.
換句話說 他們附屬於地球
In other words, they were attached to the Earth.
它們的振動頻率被調整到與地球一致
They were tuned to vibrate with the frequencies of the Earth
這樣他們就能將地球能量轉化成電磁能
and they converted the energies of the Earth into electromagnetic energy.
方尖碑本身
Obelisks themselves,
特別是埃及發現的那座
ones we find in Egypt,
實際上 是一個巨型晶體天線
are in fact, giant crystal antennas,
它們可以用類似偉大的美國發明家
and they can broadcast power in a way that Nikola Tesla,
特斯拉想要傳播能量的方式傳播能量
the great American inventor wanted to broadcast power.
是否方尖碑的建築目的
Could obelisks have been constructed
就是作為古代的能源導體？
as ancient energy conductors?
是否這種專業技術真的是人類自己的產物
And was this expertise really the product of man alone,
或是如遠古外星人理論所認為的那樣
or might it been the result of an otherworldly intelligence,
這是外星人智慧的結晶？
as ancient astronaut theorists contend?
我們都知道方尖碑象徵著眾神的能量
We do know that obelisks symbolize this power of the gods.
方方尖碑的頂端是一個小錐形 它是禁忌之石
The top of the obelisk is a small pyramid; it is a ban-ban stone.
而這塊禁忌之石據說是與神靈
And it is the ban-ban stone, which is said to have been a
溝通的通訊設備
communication device with the deities.
或許在一些金字塔的內部
It's possible that inside of some pyramids
存在 某種形式的能量 或者說
there might be some sort of energy, let's say,
某種製造波的設備
some sort of equipment, which creates waves.
所以我可以這樣設想
So I could imagine that some of the real gods,
數千年前一些真正的神
the extraterrestrials, some thousands of years ago,
外星人在金字塔中留下了一些小技術
they left some little technology inside the pyramid.
而這些技術非常超現代而且很強大
And this technology was very super modern and powerful.
是否在世界各地發現的眾多方尖碑
Could the numerous obelisks found at various sites all around the world
實際上是遠比如今任何技術都要複雜的
actually be remnants of a power system far more sophisticated
電力系統的殘骸？
than anything available today?
是否我們的祖先在數千年前
And is it possible our ancestors
就開創了某種以21世紀的標準來說
may have pioneered other types of power plants thousands of years ago,
處於尖端的發電廠？
which would be considered cutting-edge by 21st century standards?
一些人認為證據可以在遙遠的
Some believe the answer can be found
喜馬拉雅山脈找到
in the remote mountains of the Himalayas.
巴基斯坦 印度河谷
The Indus Valley,Pakistan.
1922年
1922.
印度考古調查發現了巨大的
The Indian Archaeological Survey discovers the remnants
印度河文明史前城市遺跡...
of what is the largest ancient city of the Indus Valley Civilizations...
摩亨朱—達羅
Mohenjo-Daro.
對文物和建造的分類表明
The artifacts and architecture catalogued at the site
4600年前那裡曾是一個繁華的大都市
indicate a metropolis prospered here nearly 4600 years ago.
但是在廢墟中找到的骨骼殘骸令人困惑
But the skeletal remains found among the ruins tell a puzzling story.
我明白他們在那裡發現了許多放射性塵埃
I understand that they found a lot of radioactive ash there
而且他們還在那裡發現了放射性的人
and they found radioactive people there.
因此有人猜測那裡一定發生過一些
And so the assumption is that there must've been some
輻射事件
radiation event.
又或許在很久以前那裡成發生過
And so it is possible that there was some kind of nuclear
某種原子能爆炸
explosion there a long time ago.
問題是要造成這樣的情形
The problem is that in order to do that, in order for that to be the case,
你需要一些非常先進的技術
you would have to have some very advanced technology.
這些人就死在街上
These people are just lying dead in the street.
這些就是帶有放射性的骷髏
There's radioactive skeletons.
這些是被融化的陶製品
There are ceramics that have been melted.
這看起來就像某種原子核在這個地區爆炸
It's as it some kind of atomic nuclear detonation went off in this area,
徹底的摧毀了這些城市並且殺死了所有的人
totally destroying these cities and killing everyone.
我們可以想到的是
What we may be seeing
這是一座外星人使用的
is the residue of one of the ancient
遠古發電廠的殘骸
power plants used by extraterrestrials.
是否如遠古外星人理論所認為的
But if, as ancient astronaut theorists believe,
摩亨朱—達羅是被一場核災害摧毀的
Mohenjo-Daro was wiped out in a nuclear meltdown,
這裡曾有過一座
where is the power plant
可以導致這樣大的災難的發電廠？
that might have caused such mass devastation?
西藏以西 岡仁波齊峰
Mount Kailash, Western Tibet.
這座海拔近22000英尺的山峰
At an elevation of nearly 22,000 feet,
是世界上最有特色的山峰之一
this mountain is one of the most distinctive peaks in the world.
就一座山而言它的形狀很有意思
This is a very interesting shape for a mountain.
從一側看它是圓錐形的
It is cone-shaped from one side
而從另一側看它又是金字塔形的
and pyramid-shaped from another.
而這恰恰就是我們在古蘇美爾
And this is precisely the shape we see elsewhere,in Ancient Sumeria,
古埃及和其他古文明地看到的形狀
Ancient Egypt, various other ancient civilizations whereby this
據說這種金字塔型的物體具有某種能量
pyramid-shaped object really is said to have some form of power,
某種可以聯繫神明的能量
some kind of connection with the deity.
在東方文化中
In the Eastern world,
岡仁波齊峰被當做宇宙的精神中心
Mount Kailash is regarded as the spiritual center of the universe
和四大宗教的發源地...
and the birthplace of four of the world's religions...
印度教...
Hinduism...
佛教...
Buddhism...
耆那教...
Jainism...
還有道教
and Taoism.
數千年來
For thousands of years,
宗教朝聖者長途跋涉
religious pilgrims have trekked here
來到這裡完成神聖的儀式
to perform the holy ritual
沿著山基步行走完
of walking a 32-mile circular path
32英里的環形山道
carved along the mountain's base.
每一個人在他們生命的某個時刻
Everybody at one point in their lifetime
都必須到這個地方與神聯繫
had to go to this place to connect with the gods.
而真正有趣的地方是
And this is really the interesting aspect,
到底是什麼使得這座山有別於其他山脈？
because what is it about this mountain which sets it apart from other mountains?
有這樣幾種可能性
There are several possibilities.
其中之一就是這裡確實是神明的住所
One of them is that the gods really took residence here.
是否可能如遠古外星人理論所認為的
Is it possible, as some ancient astronaut theorists speculate,
凱拉許山曾經是神明的住所
that Mount Kailash was once inhabited,
或者由神明掌控？
or perhaps operated, by the gods?
他們說這座山的真正意義可以在
They say the true significance of this mountain
一幅中國古畫中找到詳盡的解釋
can be found detailed in an ancient Chinese drawing.
中國西部 莫高窟
The Mogao Caves, Western China.
公元前500年至公元1500年
Between 500 BC and 1500 AD,
僧侶們在一些油漆的廟宇和岡仁波齊峰北部
Buddhist monks stored thousands of scrolls and manuscripts
神殿山坡深約600英里的洞窟內收藏了
inside a series of painted temples and shrines dug into a hillside
數千萬幅的卷軸和手稿
approximately 600 miles North of Mount Kailash.
1907年 匈牙利裔英籍探險家斯坦因
Here, in 1907, Hungarian-born British explorer Aurel Stein
在這裡發現了一個藏有各種語言
discovered a sealed-off room containing nearly 50,000 manuscripts
近5000手稿的密室
in various languages.
斯坦因發現的這個不可思議的地方
Aurel Stein finds this incredible place
稱為千佛洞
called the Cave of the Thousand Buddha's,
一個類似佛教記錄大廳的地方
which is sort of like a Buddhist hall of records.
這是一個收藏了成千上萬佛教古籍的地方
It's a cache of thousands upon thousands of ancient Buddhist texts.
其中包括金剛經
Included within this is the Diamond Sutra,
是已知的人類史上最古老的印刷書稿
which is the oldest printed manuscript known to human history.
這些古籍和文物的收藏中還包括
The collection of ancient texts and relics
一幅公元2世紀關於宇宙山脈須彌山的
also included a 2nd Century AD Buddhist diagram
佛教繪圖 須彌山被認為是連接天地的
of a cosmic mountain called Mount Meru... a sacred site believed to be a stairway
天梯聖地
connecting heaven and earth.
在近百年中
For nearly one hundred years,
這幅古老的畫卷並沒有引起大範圍的關注
the ancient illustration drew little notice.
但是最近 這幅圖引起了一位來自
But recently, the diagram caught the attention of a scientist
諾思拉普 - 格魯曼公司專門研發先進
from Northrup-Grumman who specializes in the development
軍事武器的科學家的注意
of advanced weapons for the military.
他說：「我依靠為政府設計的
He said, "I design particle beam weapons for
粒子束武器為生
a living for the government.
你是否意識到這是一個粒子加速器的設計圖？」
Do you realize that that's a blueprint for a particle accelerator?"
我將須彌山圖和迴旋加速器
I went and compared the diagram of Mount Meru
的圖紙進行了比較 迴旋加速器
with an illustration of what's called the cyclotron...
是一種粒子加速器
an atom smasher...
它被用於研發「曼哈頓計劃」所用的原子彈
which was used in the development of the A-bomb for the Manhattan Project.
它們非常的相似
They're a perfect match for one another.
他發現斯坦因的須彌山圖中
Aurel Stein's diagram of Mount Meru that he
似乎將須彌山繪成某種特別的粒子束
found seemed to show Mount Meru as some kind of particle beam
加速器或是某種由不同透鏡組成的設備
accelerator or some device that was stacked up, had different lenses.
這可以使它成為某種可以集中能量的設備
It would have made it into some device that focused energy.
這種能量需要巨大的發電廠供給
The kind of energy needed would have required some tremendous
某種可以提供大量能量的設備
power plant, something putting out enormous amounts of energy.
是否這幅2000多年前的須彌山圖
Might the nearly 2,000 year-old Buddhist diagram
描繪的是某種如今可以用於運轉
of Mount Meru actually depict a device that, today,
核能的設備
would run on nuclear power?
蒙古神話說這些神仙
Mongolian myth says that these celestial beings
居住在須彌山是因為它所產生的能量
dwelled around Meru because of the energy that was emitted from it.
它是一台供給這些神仙存活所需能量的
It was a transmitter of this cosmic power that fed these
宇宙能量發射器
celestial beings or kept them alive.
不管這台設備的用途是什麼
Whatever the purpose of this device was,
它都需要一些非常強大的能量來源
it would have required some extremely powerful energy source,
某種類型的核能
some type of nuclear power.
而我認為這些能量可能來自於岡仁波齊峰
And I think that power might have come from Mount Kailash.
這個地方並不產生精神能量
This wasn't a place that actually put out spiritual energy,
而是產生我們所謂的原能量
but what we're talking about is a place that produced raw energy,
技術能量
technological energy.
很可能我們在談論的就是一座發電廠
Potentially, we're talking about a power plant.
是否摩亨朱—達羅的廢墟
Could the ruins at Mohenjo-Daro
確實是喜馬拉雅山脈數千年前存在
really be evidence that a nuclear power plant existed in the Himalayas
核電站的證據？
thousands of years ago?
遠古外星人理論認為答案是肯定的
Ancient astronaut theorists say yes,
並且推測在世界各地的古文明廢墟中可以
and speculate that remnants of a world-wide power grid may be found among the sacred ruins
找到世界電力網的殘骸
of ancient civilizations all over the world.
三里島
Three Mile Island...
切爾諾貝利...
Chernobyl...
福島第一核電站...
Fukushima Daiichi...
這些曾在20世紀蓬勃發展的發電廠
These sites are now just shells of what were once
如今只是一座座空殼
thriving power plants of the 20th century.
核能被廣泛的應用在如今的基礎設施中
Nuclear power is widely used in today's infrastructure,
而且它的供給需求量很大
and it serves a very high need,
但是我們也知道核能可能變得很不穩定
but we also know that nuclear power can possibly become unstable
並且導致災難
and cause a meltdown.
是否就如我們現今看到發電廠的毀滅一樣
Just like the power plants we've seen melting down in modern times,
古人也看著他們的發電廠毀壞而這樣的失敗
the ancients saw their own power plants fail,
導致了某些偉大古文明的毀滅
and did that, in turn, cause some of the greatest civilizations to fall?
如果我們假設所有的這些發電廠
If we assume that all of these power plants
都以某種方式聯繫在一起
were somehow connected,
當一個發電廠掉線時
and one power plant went offline,
是否有可能導致另一個發電廠同樣停工？
is it possible that, as a result, the other power plants went offline, as well?
一些研究人員認為
Some researchers believe,
古代工程師就如現代工程師一般對發電廠進行了
just as modern engineers employ strategic placement of power plants today,
策略性佈局
so did the ancients...
而並非如主流科學家所認為的
and that some sacred sites
是出於精神力或儀式的目的
were not revered for spiritual or ritualistic reasons,
而選出的聖地
as mainstream scholars believe,
而是出於這些地方產生能量的能力的考慮
but actually valued for their capacity to produce energy.
某些古跡被建立在某處
Certain monuments are placed in certain locations
我們可能會認為是出於偶然
and we might think this is haphazard.
但我們終於慢慢開始意識到事實並非如此
But we are slowly beginning to realize that it is not the case.
因為不論是大金字塔
And the reason why is because whether it is the Great Pyramid,
巨石陣或是特奧蒂瓦坎
whether it's Stonehenge, whether it's Teotihuacan,
或是我們祖先所設的能量網中其他重要的能量點
whether it is another important power site of our ancestors,
我們開始意識到我們不曾記錄過的事實
we're beginning to realize that those sites have an energy
這些地點都具有能量
which we don't register at first.
古人們一定對這個世界網
There is definitely some knowledge, by ancient man,
這些能量點有一定的瞭解...
of this world grid, and these energetic points...
並且用這些古跡進行了標記
and they are marked by these monuments.
有很多的證據表明古人們與這種高性能
There is a lot of evidence that the ancients were far more connected
能源的聯繫遠勝於如今的我們
to this higher energy source than we are today.
人如果如一些研究人員所認為的那樣
But if ancient engineers pulled energy
古代工程師可以從電網中獲得能量
from a power grid, as some researchers believe,
為什麼...之後的數千年 即使不足萬年...
why... after thousands, if not tens of thousands of years...
能量停止了流動？
did the power stop flowing?
長久以來 古埃及人發展出了他們的文明
The ancient Egyptians had developed their knowledge over many years.
而其中一定存在某些工具和技術
And they must have had tools and technology
考古材料中記錄從缺
that do not exist in the archaeological record anymore.
所以當這個古文明發生某些意外時
So something happened to this ancient culture
發電廠停止了運行並且可能毀掉了
that caused the power plants to shut down and probably wiped out a large
這個文明的一大部分
portion of the civilization.
他們擁有令人難以置信的技術
They possessed incredible technology,
這就意味著他們的存在遠比我們想像的要古老
which means that they were far older than we think they are.
然後他們發生了某種意外
And then something happened to them.
不管是他們自我毀滅的戰鬥
Whether they fought, blew themselves up,
或是某些全球範圍的災難令他們滅絕
or some Earth-wide calamity came and wiped them out.
但是那些沒有輪子
But where would agrarian cultures...
或者勞作動物的農業文明
some that didn't have the wheel or work animals,
是從哪裡獲得的技術 得以建立起全球能量網
acquire the skills necessary to build a worldwide energy grid
並得到讓它運轉的能量？
and the power plants to run it?
根據遠古外星人理論
According to the ancient astronaut theory,
外星人一直都有積極推動
extraterrestrials have always been motivated by the idea
人類文明的想法
of advancing human civilization.
他們帶給我們如此多的知識作為禮物
They've given us so many gifts of knowledge
讓獲取能量變得無比容易
that power is pretty much a no-brainer.
所有古文化的共同點就是
The thing all these ancient cultures had in common
他們都包含一些故事和器物用於
is that they included stories and artifacts that are meant to honor
歌頌那些給予他們知識的「神」
those who gave them this knowledge, the "gods,"
而這些神其實就是外星人
and the gods were extraterrestrials.
是否在遙遠的過去外星人曾幫助
Is it possible that alien beings helped ancient man
古人建立了一個關於複雜發電廠的
create a global network of sophisticated power plants
全球網絡...
in the remote past...
一個可能驅動用於創造文明的裝置
one that may have powered the devices used to create
最大的考古學之謎？
civilization's greatest archaeological mysteries?
是否現代科學家才剛剛重新認識到
Are modern scientists just now rediscovering energy technology
古人精通能源技術？
mastered by the ancients?
如若如此
And, if so,
是否這些長期被遺忘的能量源的廢墟
could what remains of these long-forgotten power sources
能揭示與外星人的聯繫？
reveal a celestial connection?
一個在遙遠的過去引導人類
One that led to the advancement of the human race
走向進步的力量...
in the distant past...
是否會在將來的某一天重新回來幫助我們？
and that, perhaps, may one day return to help us in the future?